# **ALAN BRUNLINGER**

## **DATA ANALYST**



## **PROFILE**

Data Analyst who has a passion for finding the meaning of the data and conveying that as actionable information. I have 4 years of experience in Information Technology - during which I have honed my investigative thinking, understanding of correlation and causation, and the ability to craft meaningful improvements for current processes.

## SKILLS

Python: pandas, Numpy, matplotlib, seaborn,

BeautifulSoup, geopandas **Data Storage:** PostgreSQL **Excel:** Power Pivot, VLOOKUP

Data Visualization and Dashboard: Tableau,

Power BI

**Source Control/ Version Control:** Git/GitHub **Ticketing Systems:** ORACLE Peoplesoft,

ServiceNow, Jira, Salesforce

Remote Software: VMWARE, Citrix Workspace,

Mobile Device Management

## **PROJECTS**

#### Healthcare Bluebook

 Company healthcare data was provided to my team with the request of analyzing the data and reporting data trends and their underlying causes. Our team used python to bring together multiple datasets with more than 10 million rows in each, and outline a market trend of higher patient volume leading to higher procedure cost.

#### Quarantine Survey

 Survey was created using Microsoft Forms to collect a data set reflecting the participants' daily behaviors, living environment, and workload in comparison to a few factors representing their outlook on life. This information was then aggregated in Python and Power BI to identify what elements had a positive or negative contribution to a person's outlook.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Nashville Software School**

Data Analytics Bootcamp | graduation, July 2020

## **University of Tennessee**

Mechanical Engineering | 2014 (non-degreed)

## DATA ANALYTICS EDUCATION

## Nashville Software School Data Analyst | January 2020 - present

6-month intensive Data Analytics Bootcamp: Python, SQL, Excel, Tableau. Power BI

- Studied a variety of analytical and visualization tools and was encouraged to limit which tools were used on each project - to explore the tool's full capabilities and limitations when exploring, cleaning, analyzing, and then presenting the data.
- Assigned projects working with real-world data, which ranged from relatively clean or particularly dirty. While half of the projects as a member of a team, I learned that having a strong understanding of the work process and desired end product helped me to make productive contributions, and manage priorities when working independently.
- Adapted to continue work in a fully remote environment to ensure that communication was not lost in collaborative projects. Additional team work sessions were scheduled to ensure that our groups met their project deadlines.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Ceres Terminals**

2019 - 2020

Junior Systems Administrator

- Managed systems access and deployment of company software and hardware while providing continued support for all existing technologies.
- Researched technologies that could be implemented to improve IT infrastructure. Once potential improvements were evaluated, work with vendors or conduct research required to successfully implement it.
- Implemented a new knowledge base system that allowed for the team to reduce information that was siloed. Also helped establish policies that allowed for more accurate data collection on IT workload as well as develop Power BI dashboards on said data for executive and managerial

#### **UBS Financial Services**

2017 - 2019

Technical Support Representative

- Provided hardware and software solutions to Financial Advisors and Client Service Associates remotely through verbally supplied information or remote access tools.
- Worked in a constantly evolving IT environment that demanded the ability to quickly understand new tools and technologies with limited information.
- Trained additional staff on supported systems as well as developing a troubleshooting mindset to better resolve client issues.

## **US Army Reserves**

2013 - 2017

Military Police Soldier

- Worked as a member of a team in high-pressure environments where communication was key to mission success.
- Learned to ask the "right" questions when interacting with a suspect or victim in order to drive the conversation towards the truth of the matter.
- Provided reports and training on mission essential information
- Secret Security Clearance required to handle sensitive data and personnel.